<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Peter Jordan</title>
    <link>/categories/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Peter Jordan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Released under the MIT license.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 21:14:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Bang Data exhibition - a personal review</title>
      <link>/blog/big-bang-data-exhibition-apersonal-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 21:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/big-bang-data-exhibition-apersonal-review/</guid>
      <description>Last week some GDS performance and data analysts made a &amp;lsquo;field trip&amp;rsquo; down the road to the Big Bang Data exhibition at Somerset House in the Strand. The exhibition curators aim to highlight &amp;ldquo;the datafication of our world and how data affects everyone&amp;rdquo;.
The five themes in the exhibition are:
 data and you data and cities data and democracy data and privacy data and design  As an analyst working in government, I was mostly aware of the issues discussed, but I found it thought-provoking to see things represented as both data and art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAUGS VI</title>
      <link>/blog/daugs-vi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 22:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/daugs-vi/</guid>
      <description>On 4 December, I hosted DAUGS VI, the sixth meet-up of Digital Analysts in UK Government Services. What started as a smallish event for digital analysts working on the UK Government Digital Service&amp;rsquo;s Digital Transformation exemplar programme, has blossomed into a wider event for a wider family of analysts and other disciplines interested in using digital data.
Network visualisation of GOV.UK
Forty to fifty people attended DAUGS VI and we had speakers from:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>